shrewdliving.com 2015-03-15

# Privacy Policy

ShrewdLiving.com respects your privacy and is committed to protecting the personal information that you furnish. In general, you can visit ShrewdLiving.com on the Internet without identifying yourself or providing personal information. There are times when ShrewdLiving.com may need personal information from you and this Privacy Statement describes the information ShrewdLiving.com collects from you and how we may use it.

### What Information Is Collected From You?

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual. This includes but is not limited to: first and last name, email address, mailing and residential address, telephone number, title, birth date, gender, occupation, company you work for and other information needed to provide a service you have requested. When you browse our website and subsidiary sites, you do so anonymously, unless you have previously indicated that you wish ShrewdLiving.com to remember your login and password. ShrewdLiving.com does log your IP address (the Internet address of your computer) to give us an idea of which part of our website you visit and how long you spend there. However, we do not link your IP address to any personal information unless you have registered and logged in to our website. When you visit certain ShrewdLiving.com web pages, you need to be registered and to login with a password. The use of those web pages, and the information downloadable from those sites, may be governed by a written agreement between your employer and ShrewdLiving.com. Unless you request your personal information to be deleted, it may be retained by ShrewdLiving.com to verify compliance with the agreement, to track software and documents downloaded by you, or track page visits and usage of other applications available on our site. ShrewdLiving.com may receive personal information from its business partners and suppliers. ShrewdLiving.com only uses such information if it has been collected in accordance with acceptable privacy practices consistent with its policy and applicable laws.

### Uses of the information

When we collect personal information from you, we will inform you at that time of the reason we have requested it. The information will only be used for ShrewdLiving.com business purposes, such as, to respond to requests for products, documentation, and services, to process an order, to conduct a transaction, to correspond, to enable a subscription or event registration, to handle job applications or send direct marketing information and perform market research. ShrewdLiving.com will also use your information to personalize the content you view and to better understand how you use the website in order to improve the services ShrewdLiving.com provides. In general, ShrewdLiving.com assumes that you have given permission to collect and use your personal information in accordance with your acceptance of the Terms of Use, of which this Privacy Statement is a part. You have the right to request that ShrewdLiving.com not contact you for the purposes of sending you newsletters, customer surveys, direct marketing, or market research information. You can exercise this right by clicking on the appropriate option or check box at the point of collection or by editing your personal profile. In specific cases, ShrewdLiving.com will request your direct consent to use your personal information by providing an “opt-in” check box in information collection fields before it can be used for any purposes other than that for which it was given.

### Cookies

The ShrewdLiving.com Website uses cookies. A cookie is a small data file that is placed on your hard drive when you visit certain web pages. It is used to identify yourself to a website when you revisit it, to load your preferences and to track the pages you have visited. The only personal information held in such a cookie is information you have provided to ShrewdLiving.com. You have the choice of whether or not to accept cookies by means of your browser settings, although you may not be able to use certain features and functionalities of the ShrewdLiving.com website if you do disable them. If you choose to provide us with personal information, we may transfer that information, within ShrewdLiving.com or to ShrewdLiving.com’ business partners, across borders and from your country of residence or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. ShrewdLiving.com will only share identifiable information with its business partners, if you have provided us with your consent to do so. In the event that ShrewdLiving.com sells a part or parts of its business, the identifiable information that ShrewdLiving.com has collected could be transferred to the acquiring company unless you instruct ShrewdLiving.com not to do so in writing.

### Information Security

Please take note of the following to ensure information security: You should be aware that when you disclose identifiable information in the discussion forum or chat rooms, such information is accessible to and collectable by others present. ShrewdLiving.com advises you to protect yourself against unauthorized access to your computer and disclosure of your ShrewdLiving.com password. If you believe that your password has been compromised, you should immediately change your password.

### Business Relationships

During your online ShrewdLiving.com experience, you may encounter links to the sites of ShrewdLiving.com’ business partners who might include standards bodies, customers, channel customers, or suppliers. Though a connection might be made to a ShrewdLiving.com business partner site, ShrewdLiving.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of other businesses. ShrewdLiving.com strives to comply with all applicable laws around the world that are designed to protect your privacy. Although legal requirements may vary from country to country, ShrewdLiving.com intends to adhere to the principles set forth in this Privacy Statement even if, in conjunction with the above, we transfer your information from your country of residence to countries that may not require the same level of protection for your information. Our goal is to protect your information no matter where that information is collected, transported, or retained.

### Questions and Notification of Changes

If you have any questions about the ShrewdLiving.com Privacy Statement or would like to access or modify your identifiable information, please [contact us](http://shrewdliving.com/contact.php) . • The ShrewdLiving.com Privacy Statement was last updated on Oct 13, 2014. • ShrewdLiving.com reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time. Modifications to this Privacy Statement can be made without prior notification. • Continued use of the ShrewdLiving.com Websites signifies your acceptance of any changes to the Privacy Statement.
